<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Weimao Ke</title>
    <link>https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Weimao Ke</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Delight</title>
      <link>https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/project/deep-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/project/deep-delight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combines Reinforcement Learning with DLITE (Delight) as a new information measure (loss function) for training and fine-tuning of machine/deep learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Chat Analytics</title>
      <link>https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/project/library-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gethugothemes.com/academia/site/project/library-chat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in machine learning (ML) and large language models (LLMs) are offering exciting opportunities for libraries filled with precious data. This potential shines brightly in areas like chat-based assistance. Yet, there are some roadblocks - concerns about data privacy, the risk of models giving inaccurate information (hallucination), and the expenses related to tailoring and assessing these tools specifically for libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information Retrieval, often linked to the term &amp;lsquo;Reference Retrieval&amp;rsquo;, is deeply tied to library studies and services. This approach can help navigate challenges faced by LLMs. It gives us a solid framework to analyze data-driven responses. In this process, librarians also play a pivotal role and their insights and feedback are vital in ensuring that this blend of traditional library methods and cutting-edge AI truly benefits library administrators and users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
